These are all public data.
这都是公开的数据
Only someone well-versed
如果不是精通
in the finance industry
金融行业的业内人士
could find this answer.
是找不到这个答案的
And she consolidated,
而且她把这个数据
analyzed, and made judgments
做了汇总
based on the data.
做了分析和判断
What do we know about this salesperson?
这个销售员是什么底细
Not much.
她没什么底细
She used to be
她以前
a general assistant at the company,
就是公司一个勤杂啊
and before that, she was a housewife.
最早就是个家庭主妇
She hasn't been working for long.
出来工作也没多久啊
Not really.
不像
This professional report,
这份专业报告
however,
应该是出自
seems to be the work of an expert.
资深人士之手
So,
那你们说
could someone be using her
能不能是她背后
to target us?
有人想搞我们
What does she want?
那她有什么诉求
She wants to resign
她就想离职啊
and take all her commissions.
而且要拿走所有的提成
Pay her and let her leave
给她钱 让她走
with a signed confidentiality agreement.
但是要签一份保密协议
So, she was telling the truth?
那她说的是真的
Sometimes,
有时候
confidence in the financial market
金融市场的信心啊
can be shattered
会被一份小小的报告
by even
哪怕是一份
a small report,
移花接木的报告
even if it's a distorted one.
所摧毁
So,
那
the payout won't really be an issue?
兑付不会真产生问题吧
The company's senior-level payments
公司高层的兑付
are secure.
是没有问题的
You have to make sure
那你们答应我的钱
I get the money you promised.
一定要给我
Don't worry,
放心吧
the company is solid.
公司啊 肯定没问题的
Just handle this matter properly.
你先把这个事 处理好
Let's go.
我们先走
Go.
走
Wanzhen.
婉真
Mr. Qian,
钱总
these are my personal belongings.
这是我的私人物品
Please check them.
你检查一下
Wanzhen,
婉真
let's talk.
我们谈谈吧
About what?
谈什么
The report
谈那份报告
or my commissions?
还是谈我的提成
Both.
都谈谈
Here,
来
sign this agreement.
签了这份协议
With all the commissions,
还有所有提成
I'll add another 20%.
我再给你加两成
Once you walk out that door,
走出这个门
we won't know each other anymore.
我们谁也不认识谁
Looks like my report
看来我那份报告
was quite effective.
还挺管用哈
The return on investment
这投资回报率
is better than financial products.
比买理财要高一点点
What would happen
如果真相
if the clients
一旦被客户知道了
found out the truth?
会有什么样的结果啊
Wanzhen,
陈婉真
don't think
你别以为你这二把刀子
your amateurish report
炮制出来
and concocted data
什么什么什么数据的
can have any real impact
就能对公司
on the company.
造成什么影响
There are plenty of rumors
金融市场上
in the financial market,
捕风捉影的传闻多了
but none
也没看哪几个
have caused much of a stir.
造出什么风浪来啊
Yes,
是啊
like an ant trying to shake a tree,
我就是蚍蜉撼大树
I'm overestimating myself.
自不量力
Here's the amount,
给你这个数
plus all your commissions.
再加上所有提成
Is that enough?
可以了吧
Mr. Qian, I need to think it over.
钱总 我得考虑一下
I'll get back to you tomorrow.
明天答复您
Ms. Zhang,
张律师
did you review
我发给你的保密协议
the confidentiality agreement I sent you?
您看了吗
I did,
我看了
but
但是
if you sign it,
这份保密协议如果签了
it could
可能会有
give them grounds
敲诈勒索的把柄
for accusing you of extortion.
被对方拿住
If you change it
如果把它
to a contract
换成一份调查服务
for investigative services
或者是财务
or financial information provision,
信息供给的合同
it won't be a problem.
就不会有这个问题了
And you could get
而且还可以拿到
a large sum.
一大笔的钱
I can draft
我可以帮你拟一份
such a contract for you,
这样的合同
and you can negotiate with them.
到时候你去跟他们谈
Is there a way
那有没有可能
I can just get
我只拿回我应得的
my due commission
销售提成
without signing anything?
不签署任何东西
Are you thinking
你是想把这份
of making this financial report
财务调查报告
public?
公之于众吗
I haven't decided yet.
我还没有想好
I just want
我只是想
to get what I'm owed.
拿回我应得的部分
Alright.
好
But Wanzhen,
可是婉真
I still suggest you consider
我还是建议你考虑一下
accepting their settlement terms
接受对方的和解条件
and confidentiality clauses.
和保密条款
It's not a small amount, after all.
毕竟不是一笔小数目
If you get this money,
你如果拿到这笔钱
it will
首先能让你的
make your performance record
绩效工资流水
look good.
很好看
And
而且
signing
你能够和这样
a financial information supply contract
一个大型企业
with such a large company
签订财务信息的
would
供给合同
demonstrate
这说明你
your financial capabilities.
很有经济能力啊
Alright, I understand.
好的 我明白了
I'll think about it.
我再想想吧
Thank you, Ms. Zhang.
谢谢啊 张律师
Okay.
好
Dr. Yu.
俞医生
Ms. Chen.
陈小姐
Why are you sleeping in the car?
你怎么睡这儿啊
I just finished
我今天做了一台
a ten-hour surgery
十个小时的大手术
and couldn't keep my eyes open
刚开车回来实在没顶住
while driving back, so I took a nap.
就眯了一会儿
That's so dangerous,
你这也太危险了吧
driving while you're so tired.
这么累还开车
It's fine.
没事的
Ms. Chen,
陈小姐
this is also risky.
你这个也很危险
What's wrong with this?
我这怎么了
Your personal information
你这快递上面的
on the delivery label
个人信息
is too clear.
是不是太清楚了
You use your real name for deliveries?
你快递都用的真名啊
It's better to obscure personal details
个人信息最好模糊一点
or use an alias.
用化名比较好
Yes, yes,
对对对
thanks for the reminder.
谢谢提醒
Sorry.
不好意思
No worries.
没事
Dr. Yu,
俞医生
I want to ask you something.
我想问你一件事啊
Go ahead.
说
If some people
如果有一些人
don't know they're seriously ill,
不知道自己得了大病
but you do,
但是你知道
would you tell them?
你会告诉他们吗
Yes, I'd have to tell them,
得告诉他们呀
or at least inform their family.
至少也得告诉他们家属
What if they don't believe?
那要是他们不相信呢
Like the story of Bian Que and Duke Cai.
就像扁鹊见蔡桓公
If you were Bian Que,
那如果你是扁鹊
would you stay
那你会留下来是为他们
to cure them or
根除病灶 还是
take the money and leave?
拿钱跑路
Did Bian Que get any money?
扁鹊有钱拿的吗
It's just an analogy.
打一比方
I would still
我还是得
stay to help them
留下来帮他们
get rid of the disease.
根除病灶吧
After all, if I did leave,
毕竟如果我真的走了
I might feel guilty
这辈子
for the rest of my life.
可能内心也会很内疚的
We doctors have all taken an oath
我们医生都是宣过誓的
to heal and save lives.
治病救人嘛
I just remembered
我突然想起来
a story
一个故事啊
about us doctors;
是形容我们医生的
not sure if it will help you.
不知道对你有没有帮助
Go ahead.
你说
One morning
在一个暴风雨
after a storm,
过后的清晨
thousands of fish
有成千上万条鱼
were stranded on the beach.
搁浅在了海滩上面
A little boy came by
有一个小男孩路过
and started
于是他就跑过去
throwing them back into the sea
把鱼一条一条地
one by one.
丢回海里边
But being just a child,
但是他毕竟是个小孩
he could only throw one at a time,
一次只能丢一条
and very slowly.
而且丢得又慢
An adult passing by
有一个大人路过
saw this
看到了之后
and went up to the boy.
就跑过去跟那个孩子说
He said, "The sun will come out soon,
马上太阳就出来了
and by then,
等太阳一出来
these fish will all dry up.
这些鱼都会干死
Why bother?
你现在花那么大力气
You can only save a few.
只能救几条
So what's the point?
有什么用呢
Who would care?"
谁会在乎呢
The little boy,
没想到这个小男孩
without looking up,
头也不抬地
tossed another fish back into the sea
又丢了一条鱼回海里
and said,
说
"This fish would care!"
这条鱼它会在乎啊
"And this one!"
还有这一条
"This one, too!"
这一条
"This one would care as well!"
这一条它也会在乎
How about this?
怎么样 这个
No good.
不好
Looks nothing different
这跟我平常穿的校服
from my usual school uniform.
有什么区别呀
I want a performance costume.
我要的是演出服
Something like a teen idol would wear.
青春美少女那种
Got it?
懂吗
It's great!
多好啊
Graceful and poised,
大大方方
clean and neat,
干干净净
proper and decent.
正正经经的
Dad, stop picking.
爸 你别选了
Mom said she'd buy it for me.
妈说她会给我买的
And your taste...
还有你这审美吧
It's just not there.
还是差点意思
Really?
我差点意思
If that so,
我要是差点意思
could I have married your mom?
我能看上你妈妈
You should trust
你要相信
a straight man's taste.
一个直男的审美
What taste do you have?
你有什么审美呀
You're just good-looking.
你也就长得帅
Without my mom
要不是有我妈
buying those clothes for you,
买那几身衣服啊
you couldn't even leave for work.
你都没法出门上班
I go to work
我上班
because of my strong core,
那是靠着强大的内核
not the outer packaging.
不是靠外包装
At my workplace,
我在单位里
everyone who sees me
那每个人见到我
calls me
都得尊我一声
"Mr. Li".
李老师
Now "Mr." is just a general term,
现在老师都是统称
like calling someone "Sir".
跟师傅差不多
Yunjie,
李云阶
mark my words:
我就把话放在这儿
Your mom has definitely
你妈妈今天指定
forgotten about
把你这演出服的事
your performance outfit today.
给忘了
Impossible.
不可能
Why impossible?
什么不可能
Absolutely impossible.
绝对不可能
Why?
什么绝对不可能啊
Just impossible!
就是不可能
It's definitely going to happen.
一定是这样
She's so busy,
她那么忙
will she remember this?
她能记住这事
She will, for sure.
一定能记住的
Wanna bet?
打赌
Bet!
赌
Bet on what?
赌 赌什么
It's up to you.
你 你说
Treat me to fried chicken.
请我吃炸鸡
Are you crazy?
疯了吗
You dare do it with your aunt around?
你大姑在你敢吃炸鸡
We can sneak to the shop and eat.
咱俩偷偷去店里吃呀
Alright,
行吧
it's a deal.
就这么说定了
You won't win anyway.
反正你也赢不了
We'll see.
走着瞧吧
I'm back!
我回来了
You're back!
回来了
I have to hurry and draw.
我得赶紧画
Have you eaten?
吃饭了吗
Yeah, I have.
吃过了
Here, let me help.
来来 给我
Alright.
好嘞
Take it slow.
慢点啊
You're back.
回来啦
Well,
那个
your dad's home now?
你爸回家了
Yeah.
回了
Home is nicer than the hospital.
家里肯定比医院舒服嘛
And Lanxiang is looking after him.
还有兰香姐照顾着
I'm relieved.
我也放心
Yes, yes.
对对对
How about your sister's wound?
你妹妹那个伤口
It's almost healed.
恢复得差不多了
In a couple of days,
过两天
she'll move to the postnatal care center.
就转到月子中心了
Don't worry.
放心吧
Alright, have a seat over there.
好 你先 那儿坐啊
Fruit will be here soon.
水果马上来
Okay.
好嘞
Thank you, Sis.
辛苦了啊 姐
Mom,
妈
did you buy the performance outfit
我发群里的演出服
I sent in the group?
你买了吗
I...
我
I'll buy it soon.
一会儿一定买
Teen idol style.
青春美少女
What?
什么呀
Have you
你那
finished your papers?
卷子写完了吗
Bring them over for me to sign.
写完了拿来签字
It's not me asking for it;
不是我要签啊
your teacher mentioned it
是你们老师在
in the group chat.
群里边说的
Just a bit left.
还差一点
Finish it quickly.
差一点赶快写
Why bother?
何必呢
Coming back
这一回来的
to press her with homework.
就拿着作业去拿捏她
No need for that.
没必要
Am I pressing?
我这是拿捏吗
I'm encouraging, okay?
我这叫鞭策好吧
Ask any kid who got into Tsinghua
你问问哪个上清华
or Peking University,
北大的孩子
weren't they all encouraged like this?
不是被鞭策出来的
Right, Sis?
是吧 大姐
Yes, exactly.
对呀
If I hadn't pushed you,
我要不鞭策你
would you have made it to grad school?
你能考上研究生吗
See?
你看看
Come.
来来来
Have some grapes.
吃点葡萄
People say
人家说了
eating grapes
吃葡萄
makes children fair-skinned.
孩子长得白
Our second baby
我们家这二胎
is called Little Grape.
也叫小葡萄
Little Grape?
小葡萄
Named by Yunjie.
云阶给起的
What a coincidence!
这么巧
Little Grape, Little Watermelon.
小葡萄 小西瓜
Nice, nice.
好好好
I love this name.
我喜欢这个名字
So sweet.
甜哪
Finished so quickly?
这么快写好了
An invitation?
邀请函
Inviting whom?
邀请谁呀
Inviting you!
邀请你呀
How about it, Ms. Xu Meng'an?
怎么样 许梦安女士
I sincerely invite
我诚挚地邀请
You and Baby Little Grape
您携小葡萄女士
to attend my performance.
来参加我的汇报演出
To experience a spiritual cleansing,
感受一份心灵的洗礼
and also to give Little Grape
也给小葡萄
a prenatal music lesson.
上节音乐胎教
You even know about prenatal education?
你还知道胎教呢
Of course!
那当然了
You told me before,
你之前跟我说的
when I was in your belly,
我在你肚子里的时候
I even listened to classical music.
还听古典音乐呢
You said listening to classical music
还说听古典音乐
would make me smart.
还生出来聪明
I didn't say that,
这可不是我说的啊
science says so.
这是科学说的
So leave Little Grape's prenatal education
那小葡萄的胎教
to me!
就靠姐姐我喽
Hey, Yunjie,
李云阶 这
what about me?
我呢
Why isn't my name on it?
这上面怎么没我名呢
We're so close,
咱俩这么铁
we don't need formalities.
就不用了吧
Doesn't matter,
无所谓
I'll go whether I'm invited or not.
反正有没有我也得去
Your dad is feeling awkward,
你爸尴尬了
Favoring me over him.
厚此薄彼
Not encouraged!
不鼓励啊
I... I'll go comfort him.
我 我去安慰一下
You two guys,
你们这爷儿俩
over a meal of fried chicken,
为了一顿炸鸡
is it really worth it?
至于吗
Feeling jealous?
吃醋啦
Do you feel like
是不是觉着自己
after raising her so painstakingly,
辛辛苦苦养大的
I ended up picking the fruit?
结果被我摘了桃子啊
It's okay, dear.
没事 老伴
She'll surely take care of you in old age.
闺女肯定会给你养老的
Of course, that goes without saying.
那还用你说
She just sees that you're
她就是看你
pregnant,
怀孕了
and have been quite tired lately.
最近 还挺累的
So she wrote this to cheer you up.
写一写哄哄你开心嘛
Why would I be jealous?
我吃什么醋啊
If that so,
那要是真哄我的话
I'd be quite pleased.
我还真挺高兴的
But don't deny
你也不要否认
that you're feeling a bit jealous.
你吃醋这件事情
To be honest,
说实话
are you feeling
心里是不是有一点
a little sour inside?
酸酸的
Just a little,
有这么
a tiny bit.
一丢丢
I knew it!
我就说吧
It says here,
这上面写的是
4:30 p.m. on Sunday afternoon.
周日下午四点半呢
Yeah.
对啊
I thought it was in the morning,
我还以为是上午
like when she used to practice the piano.
她原来练琴那个时候呢
What's wrong?
怎么了
They notified me today
他们今天通知我
That I need to attend
说让我周日下午
an awards ceremony on Sunday afternoon.
去参加一个颁奖会
They said I've been nominated.
说我被提名了
Doesn't that clash with the recital?
那这不撞车了吗
What should we do?
那怎么办
Alright.
好嘞
I'll head out right away.
我马上就出发啊
Little fairy!
小仙女
Sis,
大姐
look at our Yunjie,
你快看我们云阶
doesn't she look graceful?
当得起亭亭玉立吧
Come, turn around.
来 转一下
Beautiful.
漂亮
Stop!
停
Two issues here.
两个问题啊
First, it's a bit plain.
第一呢 有点素
Second,
第二
wouldn't it be better
这个
to wear a vest over it?
是不是穿个马甲好点
Aunt, are you serious?
大姑 你认真的
It's a bit revealing, dear.
有点露 孩子
I think your aunt's suggestion
我觉得你大姑的建议吧
is worth considering.
可以考虑
How do you think I look in this outfit?
你们看我这身 行吗
It looks great!
太行了
I think our girl
我觉得闺女
can dress up a bit more.
可以再装扮一下
Yes, exactly!
对对对 对
Li Lin,
李临
why are you dressed so sharp?
你穿这么帅干吗啊
I have to go too.
我也得去嘛
Sis,
姐
you mean well and always speak the truth,
你是好心 净说实话
but speaking the truth
但是这说实话
should depend on the occasion, right?
那得分场合 是吧
I do know the occasion!
我分场合了
Aren't we at home now?
这不是在家吗
So, I have to speak the truth.
我就得说实话
Do you want me to lie instead?
你还要让我说瞎话
Sometimes a little white lie
偶尔说说瞎话
is acceptable,
可以的
to lighten the mood!
活跃气氛嘛
I can't win an argument with you.
我跟你啊 说不明白
Mom, you have so many
妈 你原来有这么多
girlish accessories!
少女心的饰品啊
I've never seen you wear them!
我都还没见你戴过呢
Why does this one
这个怎么连标签
still have the tag on it?
都没拆呀
It's new, of course.
新买的呗
I like this kind of
妈也喜欢这种
bling-bling stuff too.
布灵布灵的东西
But there's just
但是就是
no chance to wear them.
没有什么机会戴
Then why did you buy them?
那你还买
Such a waste of money.
浪费钱
You always lecture me!
还说我呢
Just bought them first.
先买嘛
They're all for you.
买了都留给你
Then why don't you give them to me?
那你倒是给我呀
Apart from a few hair ties,
你除了给我几个皮筋
what else have you given me?
还给过什么了
Any other good stuff?
还有什么好东西
Hand them over!
交出来
I'm saving them all for you.
都给你攒着呢
For when you go to college.
等你上大学
I knew you'd say that!
我就知道你要这么说
By the time I'm in college,
等我上大学呀
these will all be outdated.
这些都过时了
No way!
怎么会呢
This necklace looks nice.
这个项链不错
Try it on.
戴上试试
How is it?
怎么样
Looks good!
好看
But it's missing something.
还差点什么
Here, this one.
这个 来
Looks great. See for yourself!
好看 自己看看
Don't you look like a little princess?
像不像小公主
So pretty!
好好看呀
Looks nice, right?
好看吧
Alright, let's go.
那我们走吧
My little princess!
我的小公主
Meng'an,
梦安
I got a scarf.
找了一条围巾
Put it on her.
你给她搭上
Look, the color is perfect!
你 你看这颜色多好
Alright.
好
Otherwise, it's too plain.
要不然太素了
See, how bright it is!
你看 这多鲜艳哪
Right!
对
Little girls should wear bright colors.
小姑娘 就得鲜艳点
Mom, are you dressing me for winter?
妈 你这是给我过冬呢
Thank your Aunt.
谢谢你大姑
Thank you, Aunt.
谢谢大姑
The back...
后面
It's covered.
盖住了
Now, with all this air conditioning,
现在呀 你们都吹空调
you must keep your chest and back warm.
前后心一定要护好
Got it?
知道吗
You're right.
大姑说得对
We're out of time; we need to go.
我们到时间了 得走了
Alright, you go ahead.
好好好 你们先走吧
Bye, Aunt.
拜拜 大姑
Okay, bye-bye.
好 拜拜 拜拜
None of you are easy.
没有一个省心的
I really can't stand this.
最受不了这种了
And you're still siding with Aunt!
你还帮着大姑说话
From a health perspective,
养生学上讲
your aunt is right.
你大姑是对的
Aesthetically, maybe not so much.
这美学上是差点意思
Just go along with her a bit.
你就顺着点你大姑
What's the harm?
能怎么的
Mom,
妈
you really are two-faced.
你真是阳奉阴违
First place!
第一名了
Ladies,
二位女士
the car has been checked.
车况已经检查过了
You may get in.
可以上车
Please.
请
Dad, you look so handsome today!
爸 你今天真帅
Now even drivers
司机现在
are as handsome as you?
都像你这么帅了吗
Industry competition, you know.
行业内卷啊
No PDA in front of me!
不许在我面前撒狗粮
We're married, okay?
我们合法的好吗
Let's go.
走了
Watch carefully.
看着啊
He is going to open the car door for me.
你爸要给我开车门呢
Here we go!
走喽
Driving feels great today.
今天开车的心情真好
Like I'm riding the waves!
有一种乘风破浪的感觉
Keep it steady, please!
你给我稳住啊
Mom,
妈
you're amazing!
你真厉害
Top 10 in the city!
全市前十呢
Maybe you'll even win first place today.
没准今天还能得第一呢
No, I'm just a nominee.
不是 我就是个提名啊
Let's not exaggerate,
咱不吹
okay?
好吧
Out of ten winners,
十个得奖的
you're definitely one of them!
肯定有你
I'm so proud!
我太骄傲了
Last night, I was even upset
我昨天晚上还因为
because you couldn't come with me
你不能陪我去
to my performance.
汇报演出闹情绪呢
I take back what I said.
我收回我的话
Bring back a big trophy!
拿个大奖杯回来
I feel like I've already won!
我觉得我已经赢了
Won my daughter's approval.
赢得了女儿的认可
My mom is awesome.
我妈真厉害
If I could make it to the city's top 10,
我要是能成为全市前十
no,
不
even the top 100...
哪怕是前一百
Your mom would smile in her sleep!
你妈做梦都能笑醒啊
Your dad would faint from happiness.
你爸能笑背过气去
I was just saying.
我就随口一说啊
Don't pressure me.
别给我压力
Yunjie,
云阶
if you have an idea,
既然想了
you have to act on it.
就要付出行动
The reason your mom
你妈之所以
has her achievements today
能够有今天的成绩
is entirely because of her
完全就是因为她
strong execution.
执行力强
How about letting me
要不你的学习
take over your studies?
妈妈来执行一下
No need!
不用
Look at you two!
你看你们俩这样
Hello, Ms. Zhang, good morning.
喂 张律师 早上好
Wanzhen,
婉真
I've sent you the electronic draft
供给合同的电子稿
of the supply contract.
我已经发给你了
I've made a few more revisions.
我又做了一点修改
There should be no
现在应该没有
legal loopholes now.
任何的法律漏洞了
You can now secure legal financial rights
你可以为你和你的孩子
for you and your child.
争取合法的经济权益了
I'm truly happy for you.
真是替你感到高兴
Ms. Zhang,
张律师
I've thought about it all night.
我想了一晚上
I've decided
我打算
to give up the money.
这个钱不要了
Why?
为什么呀
That's your hard-earned money!
这是你的劳动所得啊
At least
至少
get your performance bonus back.
把你的绩效拿回来吧
Then, could you help me check
那你再帮我看一看
If I make this report
如果我把这份报告
publicly available,
公开于世的话
what kind of legal responsibility
我要承担
will I face?
什么样的法律责任呢
There won't be any legal risks.
不会有任何法律风险的
These data
这些数据
were obtained through public sources,
都是你公开所得
and you're simply exercising
而且你只是行使了
your right to commercial oversight.
一个公民的商业监督权
Of course, they might
当然了 他们也有可能
decide to sue you,
会对你提起诉讼
but if it comes to that,
但是如果要打官司的话
I'm confident we can win.
我也有信心可以打赢
Hearing you say that
您这么说的话
puts me at ease.
我就放心了
But why
只是你为什么
don't you want the money?
不要这个钱呢
You're divorced,
你离了婚
and you could use the money.
本来也需要钱哪
I think
我觉得
there are more important things to do.
还有更重要的事情要做
Thank you, Ms. Zhang.
谢谢你啊 张律师
Alright.
好吧
Goodbye.
再见
That's great.
真好
I should work hard too.
我也要好好努力
Next time, have Rachel
下次让瑞秋啊
sign me up as well.
把我也报上
Okay.
好
Go for it.
加油
Grab something to eat. Want to join?
我去吃点东西 你去吗
No, thanks. You go ahead.
我不去了 您去吧
Thanks.
谢谢
Miss Huang always has interesting ideas.
黄小姐一直挺有想法的
Indeed she does.
确实是
I just follow the boss's lead.
我都听老板的
Excuse me.
我去一下
Alright, alright.
好好好
You finally showed up.
你可算来了
They've been driving me crazy.
别扭死我了
Still hanging out with Huang Sisi?
还跟黄思思一块儿混呢
And you still want to remarry?
就这你还想复婚
You're quite conflicted.
你挺分裂啊
I'm totally conflicted right now.
我现在我就是特别分裂
I have no choice.
我没办法
Right now, I'm
我现在是
being held hostage by the investors.
被投资人给绑架了
You know,
你说她
she's an executive in our company,
算是我们公司的高管
right?
对吧
The investors won't let her leave,
投资人不让她走
so I can't force her out.
她不走我又不能赶她走
Right?
对不对
Right now,
现在正是我
my company is at a critical point.
公司最关键的时候
I can't afford to cause any disputes.
我不敢引起纠纷哪
But I've heard that Huang Sisi
可我怎么听说黄思思
has contacted a headhunting company
联系了猎头公司
and has been frequently in touch
还跟各大公司的老板
with various company bosses.
联系频繁啊
She knows very well
她自己心里面啊
in her heart
她也清楚
that once her contract
只要她跟我蓝海的
with Blue Ocean expires,
劳动合同一到期
I won't renew it.
我是不会续约的
By then,
到时候就算是
we'll part on good terms.
好聚好散
And no one will bother the other.
谁也不碍谁的事
But you need to give me some time.
但是你得给我点时间呀
Right?
对吧
We're almost at that point.
很快就办到这一步了
It's not easy for me either.
我也不容易
She finally managed
这好不容易
get Wanzhen out of the picture.
把婉真给解决走了
Can she really leave you amicably?
她能跟你好聚好散
I find that hard to believe.
我怎么那么不信呢
So, I'm really in a tough spot.
所以说这事我太冤枉了
Think about it,
你说
if I were involved with her,
如果我跟她有关系
would she let me off easily?
那 那她能轻饶了我
Wouldn't she
她不得把我
make my life hell?
往死了折腾啊
I really
我真的跟她
have nothing to do with her.
半毛钱关系都没有
How about this...
你这么着
Let Wanzhen
你让婉真
see my actions.
看我的行动
Since the divorce, Wanzhen
人婉真离婚以后
has been living quite well.
日子过得挺滋润的
She looks even prettier now.
人也变得特漂亮
What's there to see in your actions?
看你什么行动啊
Stop acting.
你别行动了
It's impossible.
不可能
She's just toughing it out.
硬撑着呢
A woman,
一个女人
raising two kids while working.
带着俩孩子还工作
Don't worry.
你放心啊
I won't be like someone,
我不会是那陈世美
abandoning my wife and kids.
抛妻弃子的
I won't give up.
我不会放弃的
No, wait,
不是
Who gave up on whom back then?
你俩当初谁放弃的谁啊
Don't make me sound so terrible.
别把我说得那么不堪
Okay?
行不行
Can't you wish me something good?
你能不能盼我点好啊
I'm just making you face reality.
我让你面对事实
Once my company's
等我公司啊
funding issue is resolved,
融资问题我解决了
I'll be free
我腾出手来
to win Wanzhen
我再把我们家婉真
back.
给追回来
I'll throw a grand wedding,
我再办一个盛大的婚礼
with the best cars,
到时候什么这个 车呀
and the scenic route,
这个游车的路线呀
hotel,
酒店
food, drinks, cigars,
吃的 喝的 烟
right?
是吧
I'll upgrade everything.
这我全面升级
Even the guests will be upgraded.
到时候宾客也升级了
Not like years ago, right?
不比若干年前了 对吧
Then tell me,
那你说
should my gift money
我这红包
also be upgraded?
是不是也得升级啊
I never thought,
我真没想到啊
I,
我
in this lifetime,
这辈子
would get to have a second wedding.
还能结第二回婚
Of course, it's with my Wanzhen.
当然 是跟我们家婉真
You better come then.
到时候你也得来啊
And upgrade your gift too.
你这红包也得升级
Shameless!
不要脸呢
Make sure to buy a lot.
一定要多买
Listen to Mengyi talk to you.
听我们梦伊跟你们聊
It's really good.
非常好
I bought a lot myself.
我自己买了很多的
The profit is quite high.
这利润挺高的
Let me explain it well.
我给你好好介绍一下啊
Alright.
好
But this time,
但是这个
uncles and aunties,
几位叔叔阿姨
make sure to listen to
一定要听我们
Rui this time.
蕊蕊聊 这次
It's really good.
这次非常好
Make sure to buy, okay?
一定要买哦
Let me show you.
给你们看一下
I'll think about it.
我考虑一下
How about it?
怎么样
Anything you don't understand?
有什么不明白的吗
If you don't understand, you can ask
不明白的可以问一下
our sales staff.
我们销售人员
Uncles, aunts,
叔叔 阿姨
the investment
这个理财啊
comes with risks.
是有风险的
You must be cautious when buying.
你们购买一定要谨慎啊
The debt ratio of Huaxing Company
这华謃公司的负债率
has exceeded the warning line.
已经超过警戒线了
You all worked hard to earn this money.
大家辛辛苦苦赚点钱
Don't let it go to waste.
不要打水漂了
Take a look.
你们看一下
This is probably the only chance.
应 应该就这么一次
What's being sent?
发什么呢
So,
所以
make sure to seize this opportunity.
一定把握住这次机会
Don't listen to her.
你们别理她
She's a salesperson for this company.
她是这个公司销售员
Look,
你们看一下
she's competing with our salesperson
是跟我们那个销售员
for business.
在抢生意呢
She wants to take the share
她想把我们
we have earned.
得到的那个份额切走
Everyone, just ignore her.
大伙都别理她
Feifei, Feifei.
菲菲 菲菲
Uncle Liu, don't get angry!
刘叔叔 刘叔叔 别生气
Feifei,
菲菲
that woman competing with you for business
那个跟你抢生意的人
is here again.
又来了
Don't be angry, calm down.
别生气 消消气啊
Wanzhen,
陈婉真
what do you want?
你干什么呀
we're all from the same company.
都是一个公司的
If you don't sell investment products,
你不卖理财
don't ruin our livelihoods.
你也别砸我们饭碗哪
Exactly.
就是
I have already resigned.
我已经提出离职了
I'm no longer with the company.
现在不是公司的人
I'm just fulfilling my duty
我在尽一个公民的
as a citizen.
监督责任
You can
你们可以
sell your investment products,
卖你们的理财产品
But I can also remind everyone
但是我也可以提醒大家
that investments come with risks, right?
理财有风险吧
Take a look.
你们看一下
This is the company's financial report.
这是公司的财务报表
The elders might not understand it,
叔叔阿姨看不懂
but as salespeople, you should.
你们销售应该看得懂
If
如果
the bank tightens loans to the company,
银行对公司收紧贷款
then the investment products
那么理财产品
will face difficulty in repayment.
就会有兑付困难
Take a look at this.
你们看一下
Feifei,
菲姐
there seems to be a problem.
好像是有点问题啊
I'll go ask Mr. Qian.
我去问问老钱
Uncle, please take a look.
叔叔 您看一下
Hello?
喂
I'm going to find Chen Wanzhen now
我现在就去找陈婉真
and have her sign the agreement.
让她把协议签了
The profit and commission you promised me
你答应我的收益和提成
must be delivered.
一定要兑现
Mr. Qian,
钱总
look at this.
您看这个
Is what Wanzhen said true?
婉真姐说的是真的吗
Where is she?
陈婉真呢
Congratulations to all
恭喜各位
the outstanding women in the industry
行业中的杰出女性
for winning
获得了
the Top 10 Influential Women
春江市互联网产业
in the Chunjiang Internet Industry.
十大影响力女性人物
All of you are local
各位呢 都是我们本地
heroines in the Internet industry.
互联网行业的巾帼英雄
Let's give them another round of applause.
再一次掌声鼓励她们
Now, let's invite our
那有请我们的
outstanding women to take their seats.
杰出女性先行就座
Come.
来
Wonderful.
真好
Take it.
拿着吧
Host,
主持人
I have something to say.
我有话想说
This outstanding woman
这位杰出女性
has some words to share
看来是有什么获奖感言
upon receiving the award.
想要和大家分享
Please, go ahead.
有请
Thanks.
谢谢
Dear colleagues,
各位同仁
good afternoon.
午安
I'm Huang Sisi,
我是蓝海传媒的
the Content Director
内容总监
of Blue Ocean Media.
黄思思
I am especially grateful to everyone
特别感谢大家
for your recognition.
对我的认可
Although
这个
this is a personal award,
虽然是颁给我的个人奖
it represents the collective wisdom
但它是蓝海传媒
of everyone at Blue Ocean Media.
所有人的智慧结晶
Standing here,
那我站在这里
the person I most want to thank
最想感谢的那个人
is also present today,
他今天也在场
my mentor,
我的伯乐
Mr. Yu Hai,
蓝海传媒总裁
the President of Blue Ocean Media.
于海先生
Mr. Yu,
于先生
without you,
如果没有您
there wouldn't be
就没有今天
me standing here today.
站在这里的黄思思
I want to dedicate this award
我要把这个奖
to you.
送给你
Well said!
说得好
Miss Huang
黄小姐呀
is truly grateful
这是吃水不忘挖井人
and knows how to repay kindness,
知恩图报
a role model for modern women.
是当代女性的楷模
Cringeworthy.
辣眼睛
Wanzhen,
陈婉真
are you here
你是故意来
to ruin my moment on purpose?
拆我台的是吗
Didn't you agree
你不是已经答应我们
to sign the agreement with us?
要签协议了吗
Why are you still spreading
为什么还要散布这些
this false information?
虚假的信息
Mr. Qian,
钱总
are you referring
你说的
to this confidentiality agreement?
是这个保密协议吧
Is this the one?
是不是这个
Mr. Qian, I'm sorry.
钱总 对不起
I've decided
我决定
to give up both the money
这钱跟提成
and the commissions.
我都不要了
Feifei,
菲菲
stop urging people
你们不要再鼓动大家
to buy the investment products.
买理财了
Quickly redeem
你们自己买的
what you've bought yourselves.
也赶紧兑付了
Otherwise, once the financial market
否则金融市场
reveals the company's
一旦披露公司的
financial statements,
财务报表
the investment products
理财产品呢
will also face
也会产生相应的
repayment issues.
兑付问题
Ask Mr. Qian
你问问钱总
if his money has been redeemed.
他的钱有没有兑付
Stop talking nonsense here.
你别在这儿胡说啊
I'm sticking with the company!
我跟公司共进退
Mr. Qian, you're a smart man.
钱总 你是聪明人
After seeing that report,
看到那份报告
you should know what's going on, right?
应该知道怎么回事了吧
When the company is about to collapse,
大厦将倾
the first to exit
理财产品一旦爆雷
are those in the know
最早退场的
before the investment products default.
就是最先知情的人
And those left holding the bag
那接盘的呢
are these innocent people.
就是这些无辜的老百姓
Feifei,
菲菲
Mr. Wu,
老吴
you know how much you have bought,
你们自己买了多少
don't you?
心里有数吧
Wanzhen,
婉真姐
what should we do now?
那现在该怎么办啊
We demand immediate redemption.
我们要求马上兑付
Yes, yes.
对 对
We won't be the scapegoats.
不做接盘侠
Thank you to Zhouzhou
感谢州州
for the wonderful performance.
为我们带来的精彩曲目
Next, let's welcome
接下来有请
Wang Yunxi
王韵熙同学
to perform
为我们带来的
Etude in B minor.
B级练习曲
Excuse me.
不好意思啊
Sorry.
不好意思 不好意思
Dad,
爸
I changed my number six to NO. 8.
我把六号换成八号了
Mom should be able to make it, right?
应该能等到我妈来吧
You changed it?
你去换的
You're something!
你厉害啊
Alright.
行
Mom went on stage to get an award!
我妈上台领奖啦
Mom looks beautiful!
我妈就是漂亮
So elegant!
有气质啊
What number is it now?
现在几号了
No. 6 now.
六号了
It's currently NO. 6.
现在六号了
You're NO. 8.
你八号
Isn't it almost your turn?
这不 马上到你了吗
Yes.
对呀
No,
不行
I have to call your mom
我得给你妈挂个电话
and tell her to come quickly.
让她 让她赶紧过来呀
Go on, sit down properly.
去去去 好好坐着
Sit down, sit down.
坐着 坐着
Hello, honey,
喂 老公
I'm done here.
我这边结束了啊
I'll be there right after a quick stop.
上个厕所马上就来
Alright.
行
Tell the driver
让司机在
to speed up
注意安全的情况下
safely.
提速啊
Mom,
妈
I just saw the photo of you
我刚看到你
receiving the award on stage.
上台领奖的照片了
You're beautiful and powerful,
又美又强
better than a celebrity.
赛过明星呢
Thanks, sweetheart.
谢谢闺女
I'll be there soon.
我马上到啊
Alright, I'm waiting for you.
好 我等你
You really know how to lay it on thick.
这彩虹屁吹得可以啊
I'm just telling the truth.
我这实话实说罢了
Why are you out again?
怎么又出来了
Go back inside.
进去
Hurry up.
快快快
Did I say something wrong?
我说错了吗
You really are my mentor.
你确实是我的伯乐呀
And you did discover me.
也确实是你发掘的我啊
Wait, are you out of your mind?
不是 我说你疯了吧你
Performing for an audience?
你表演型人格啊
Who are you trying to impress?
演给谁看呢你
How am I acting?
我哪里演了
Every word I said is true.
我句句真心啊
Even if you kick me out,
就算你赶我走
I'll still be grateful you discovered me.
我也要感激你挖掘了我
Can we stop this act, please?
咱别演了 好不好
Once the contract ends,
合同到期了之后
you can just leave.
你直接给我走人
You go your way,
你走你的阳关道
I'll go mine.
我走我的独木桥
We're not connected.
咱俩没关系
Aren't you embarrassed?
嫌不嫌丢人哪
As long as I'm not embarrassed,
只要我不尴尬
the awkwardness is on others.
尴尬的就是别人
Fine.
好
You win.
算你狠
What's wrong?
怎么了
Not feeling well?
不舒服
It's nothing.
没事
Just feeling a bit nauseous.
就是有点恶心
I'm leaving now.
先走了
Quite attentive, aren't you?
够殷勤的呀
Still waiting here.
还在这儿等着
Yeah, yeah, waiting for what?
是 是 等什么
Your prized find.
你的千里马啊
Why wait for her? I'm waiting for you.
我等她干吗 我等你呢
I'm not your mentor.
我又不是你伯乐
Why wait for me?
等我干吗
No, it's just...
不是 那个
Where are you headed?
你去哪儿啊
I'll drive you.
我开车送你
No need.
不用了
I'm going to find my daughter.
我找我女儿去
Come on, just get in my car.
你别介 你坐我车
Let's talk.
咱俩聊聊呗
I don't want to talk.
不想聊
I have some intel.
我可有情报啊
Interested?
感兴趣
You're no fun.
你这没意思啊
We've been friends
你说咱俩朋友
for over 20 years,
二十多年了
and now
我想跟你聊个天
I need to use intel
还得拿情报
to chat?
这事勾引你啊
Are you coming or not?
你走不走
Alright, alright, let's go.
走走走 走
Get in my car.
上我车
What's that smell in your car?
你这车里什么味啊
No smell at all.
没什么味啊
Is it the car freshener?
是不是车载香水啊
Hey,
师傅
who bought this air freshener?
你这香水谁买的
Miss Huang gave it to us.
我们黄总监送的
Stop the car.
停车
It's nauseating.
恶心
I want to get out.
我要下车
No, no, no.
别别别
What are you doing?
这 这干吗呀
Lv.
小吕
Yes, Mr. Yu?
于总 您说
Well,
那个 那个
is that a trash can up ahead?
前面就是垃圾桶吗
Quick, throw that air freshener away.
赶紧把这香水给我扔了
Got it, Mr. Yu.
好的 于总
I had no idea who bought it.
我又不知道谁买的
It's disgusting.
恶心人
Makes me want to vomit.
想吐
Such a big reaction.
那么大反应
Are you pregnant?
怀孕啦
Really pregnant?
真怀孕了
Unbelievable.
不行啊
Wait, my Senior Li Lin
不是 我这李临师哥
is really something.
真够可以的
Making you earn money outside,
让您在外边赚钱养家
and now having you bear a baby?
还让您跟这儿生孩子啊
Wanzhen
婉真
hasn't earning for you.
倒是没替你赚钱养家
Where is he now?
人呢
Hitting the sore spot, huh?
哪壶不开提哪壶是吧
Can you chat properly?
会聊天不
Nope.
不会
Wait,
不是
your career is quite stable now,
你这现在事业挺稳定的
on the rise.
蒸蒸日上的
Your position is solid.
位子坐那么稳
Why have a baby now?
这干吗呀 生个孩子
I'm having it because I'm pregnant.
怀了就生呗
I talked to Mr. Zhang about it.
我跟张总也说过了
Anyway, now it's no longer
反正现在也不是
a secret.
什么秘密了
So,
我说的呢
this matter is all out in the open.
这事都公开了
I'm telling you,
我跟你说
I was just about to bring this up.
正要跟你说这事
Mr. Zhang is now scouting for people.
张总现在四处挖人呢
Is he trying to replace you?
是不是要把你给替喽啊
Gotten wind of it.
收到风声啦
Lv,
小吕
put on your headphones.
那个 你把耳机戴上
Poor thing.
你也真可怜
Even the driver isn't yours?
司机都不是你的人吗
Better safe than sorry.
小心驶得万年船
Mr. Zhang is recruiting,
张总现在挖人
and he's reached Huang Sisi.
挖到黄思思这儿了
Is that supposed to be intel?
这算什么情报啊
I knew that long ago.
我早知道了
But Huang Sisi can't make it.
但是黄思思去不了
The salary and position she wants
她要的薪资和位置
are things Mr. Zhang can't offer.
张总给不了
That was the first negotiation.
那是第一次谈判
If Huang Sisi
黄思思
knew you were pregnant,
如果知道你怀孕了
she'd know that
那她就知道
you'd have a vacancy
在这个位置
in your position.
你肯定有一空窗期
When you're not in the company,
你不在公司
right?
对不对
If they negotiate again,
他俩要是再谈一次判
and each makes a compromise,
各让一步
your position could
那你那会儿这位置
be in jeopardy.
可就悬了
Thank you.
谢谢啊
Let me tell you,
我跟你说啊
Huang Sisi,
这个黄思思啊
I know her very well.
我非常了解
She's very shrewd
那心思非常地活
and loves taking shortcuts.
特别爱走捷径的一女孩
Be careful.
你小心
Shortcuts are the longest route.
捷径就是最大的弯路
I'm not afraid.
那我不怕了
Just be careful yourself.
自己小心
Thanks to Youyou
感谢悠悠
for the wonderful performance.
为我们带来的精彩曲目
Next up, please enjoy
接下来 请欣赏
the sonata performed by Qin Xiyi,
秦希怡带来的奏鸣曲
the first movement of G Major Sonata.
G大调第一乐章 海顿
I've switched to No. 12.
我都换成十二号了
How much longer do you need?
你还有多久啊
I'm stuck in traffic!
堵在路上啦
Hurry up, speed it up.
赶紧 抓紧
Your daughter is about to go on stage.
你闺女马上就要上场
I'll definitely be there.
来 来 我肯定来
There's traffic on the road.
这不路上堵车呢吗
Just wait a bit.
稍等会儿呗
It looks like your mom
我看来你妈呀
is really stuck in traffic.
是真的是堵路上了
Maybe just forget it.
要不就算了
Don't let her come.
别让她来了
No way!
不行
It was my mom
钢琴还是我妈
who made me learn the piano.
让我学的呢
Today is the last lesson.
今天最后一节课了
Mom, I hope you can make it.
妈 我希望你能来
Yes.
对
Sweetie, mom will definitely be there.
宝贝 妈妈肯定到啊
Well,
那个
maybe you could tell the teacher
要不然你跟老师说一下
to move a few acts behind?
咱往后边串几个节目
I'm already the last.
我都已经垫底了
How can that be the last?
这怎么能叫垫底呢
That's called the finale.
那叫压轴
You're so well-prepared,
我女儿准备得那么充分
you must be the finale.
必须压轴
Ms. Xu Meng'an,
许梦安女士
if you don't come,
爱来不来
don't regret it.
不来别后悔
Wait.
你等等
Your mom said she'd be here for sure.
你妈说了 她肯定来
Don't worry.
放心吧